Georgiy Mamedaliev

Senior MLOps/DevOps/Cloud Engineer

9+ years of experience in AWS and Azure, both from cloud infrastructure automation and DevOps (CI/CD) perspectives, boosted with Kubernetes, Python programming, SRE mindset, and architectural thinking. Passionate about (almost addicted to) NLP and Machine Learning.

US Green Card holder.

EXPERIENCE

Invitae

Lead MLOps/DevOps Engineer (Tech Lead)

Jan 2022 - Present | Remote

- Leading MLOps-related activities across the company. Managing and mentoring MLOps and DevOps teams.
- Designing MLOps pipelines with continuous training approach with data drift (Kubeflow with experiments tracking in Weights & Biases), mostly for NLP and CV
- Designing and implementing inference services architecture based on KServe, with high availability and disaster recovery, API gateway design (FastAPI + OpenAPI/Swagger), Streamlit/Gradio apps
- Autoscaling optimization of inference with event-driven architecture, with thorough and almost fanatic costs reduction approach
- · Building continuous feedback components with monitoring of ML workloads and data drift.
- CI/CD automation for ML and customer-facing services, building monitoring and alerting stack based on Grafana and Prometheus, Argo Workflows jobs orchestration for data engineering routines
- Infrastructure as Code with Terraform and GitOps for Kubernetes (Flux CD, ArgoCD)
- Cloud governance, SecOps and costs related policies guidelines for eng teams; platform engineering portal design and development (backstage.io)

DealerSocket (acquired by Solera)

Senior System/DevOps Engineer

Aug 2015 - Jan 2022 | Irving TX

- Led DevOps transformation initiatives across company tribes
- Designed and implemented Continuous Integration/Delivery (and even Continuous Deployment) pipelines and sibling tools.
- IaC based on CloudFormation, ARM and Terraform for wide range of AWS, Azure services. Configuration management with Chef and Ansible.
- K8s, including AWS EKS, ECS and Azure AKS, with Helm charts.
- Designed and maintained monitoring systems for various architectural patterns, services, workflows, NOC/CAB/Change management activities, cloud governance, policies, documentation, and conventions. Coaching teams in related activities.
- Dreamed about chaos engineering across all company services someday:-) (as proof of quality, high availability and resilience).

DealerFire (acquired by **DealerSocket**)

Release Engineer, Web Developer

Sep 2009 - Aug 2015 | Oshkosh WI, Kaliningrad Russia, Tashkent Uzbekistan

- Designed and maintained CI/CD pipelines.
- Collaborated with dev teams and coordinated risk assessment, evaluated timelines, contingency plans, and orchestrated deployment activities across organizational boundaries.
- Built monitoring system of QA stages, driving product releases across different systems and teams. Custom solution on AWS ECS orchestrated by Python Django app.
- Worked closely with the Architecture guild to maintain and enhance release and testing strategies. Built product modules in PHP and JS.

EDUCATION

Termez State University

B.S. Computer Information Systems and Economics (dual major)

Sep 2001 - Aug 2005

Mathematical Statistics, Probability Theory, Macroeconomic and Sectoral Analysis, Computer Science, Management

Dallas, TX (Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex) (920) 312-6589

gmamedaliev@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/georgiy-m amedaliev

SKILLS

- AWS, Azure
- Terraform, CloudFormation, ARM (AzureRM) templates
- CI/CD (Github Actions, Jenkins, Azure DevOps/Pipelines, TeamCity, GitLab, Bitbucket Pipelines, Octopus, JFrog/Artifactory, SonarQube)
- Kubeflow, Argo Workflows, Weights and Biases, KServe, Istio, Knative, Label Studio
- Docker, Kubernetes (AWS EKS, Azure AKS, Rancher, ECS), Helm, Flux, ArgoCD, Karpenter
- Grafana, Prometheus, NewRelic, CloudWatch, Vault, Azure Monitor & Application Insights, Sentry, Datadog, Zabbix, LogicMonitor, OpsGenie, PagerDuty, ELK
- PyTorch, Keras/Tensorflow, FastAPI, Streamlit, Gradio, Jupyter, AWS SageMaker, Google Cloud Al Platform / Vertex Al
- · Ansible, Chef
- Python, Rust (basic), Go (basic), Bash, Powershell
- JavaScript, PHP
- IIRA, VersionOne, Azure Boards

CERTIFICATES

- AWS Solutions Architect Professional SAP-C01
- Microsoft DevOps Engineer Expert AZ-400
- Microsoft Azure Administrator AZ-104
- Deep Learning & Machine Learning Specializations Coursera
- Natural Language Processing Coursera

LANGUAGES

 English, Russian (native), Uzbek

Georgiy Mamedaliev

• Wylie, TX, US

Contact Information

• s3f-5pd-qcj@mail.dice.com

Summary

Being like Bill Palmer at Parts Unlimited (from "The Phoenix Project: A Novel about IT, DevOps, and Helping Your Business Win" by Gene Kim)

Work History

Total Work Experience: 15 years

- Lead Mlops/Devops Engineer (Tech Lead) Invitae
 Jan 01, 2022
- Senior System/Devops Engineer Dealersocket
 Aug 01, 2015
- Release Engineer, Web Developer Dealerfire Sep 01, 2009

Education

• Bachelors | Termez State University

Skills

- amazon web services 9 years
- architecture 9 years
- cicd 9 years

- cloudops 9 years
- devops 9 years
- **sre** 9 years
- kubernetes 6 years
- machine learning 6 years
- pytorch 6 years
- kubeflow 4 years
- mlops 4 years
- · artificial intelligence
- deep learning
- lamp
- linux
- mysql
- · neural networks
- php
- python
- sql
- web development
- ansible 9 years
- azure 6 years
- chef 6 years

Work Preferences

- Desired Work Settings: Remote or On-Site or Hybrid
- Likely to Switch: True
- Willing to Relocate: True
- Travel Preference: 0%
- Work Authorization:
 - o US
- Work Documents:
 - o Green Card Holder
- Security Clearance: False
- Third Party: False
- Employment Type:
 - o Full-time

Profile Sources

- linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgiy-mamedaliev
- linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/georgiy-mamedaliev-0877665
- github: https://github.com/gerchik

- facebook: https://facebook.com/georgeouz
- Dice:

https://www.dice.com/employer/talent/profile/c0784c41f941e03921104a8bd3615536